

Profile

I am a Fullstack Developer, mainly focused in Javascript. I have experiences working with banking, retail and transport industries.

I have worked with a lot of technologies and frameworks like Angular 2+, Vue.js, Node.js, Java and C#. I also have some experiences with cloud services like AWS (Lambdas and Step Functions) and MS Azure (APIs and Databases).

My experiences allowed me to also work with Relational Databases (Postgres and SQL Server) and a bit of NoSQL (MongoDB).

I am always willing to learn something new and always open to learn new technologies! I also like to work under Agile methods and Scrum/Kanban teams as well.

Employment History

Full-stack Developer at Terminal.io, Santiago

April 2023 — Present

Full-stack Developer with Typescript, Angular and NestJS for Terminal.io clients.

Fullstack Developer at LTT Labs - Floatplane, Santiago

October 2022 — January 2023

Fullstack position for LTT Labs's internal projects, their maintenance and development. We used Next.js and Contentful for integrating webhooks, with Opensearch as their search index in order to bring value to LTT Labs's new web portal.

Skills: Next.js · JavaScript · Node.js · React.js

Fullstack Developer at Consorcio, Santiago

July 2022 — October 2022

Fullstack Developer role for Consorcio's internal clients. Integrations, backend engineering, teaching best practices and helping the internal teams to implement new technologies like APMs and APIs.

Skills: Vue.js · TypeScript · NestJS · Node.js · Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Backend Developer at X-Team, Santiago

June 2021 — March 2022

Backend Developer role for Rstudio, specializing in Node.js and Microservices with Express.js.

Details

Los Alerces 3225 Apt. 28 Santiago Chile

+56963449698

francisco.gonzalez.lorca@gmail.com

Date / Place of birth

1985-05-27

Santiago de Chile

Nationality

Chilean

Links

Github Portfolio

Skills

React.js

Git

Angular

CSS

HTML5

HTML

PHP

jQuery

MongoDB

MySQL

Node.js

HTML & CSS

SOL

C#

Programming

.NET

- I helped Rstudio integrate and improve their services in order to ease and speed up it's Business Automation process, in order to help the License purchasing process a 50% faster with their salespeople and their clients.
- For that, I learned and worked with Salesforce APIs, OAuth Integrations, webhooks, AWS Lambdas and Step Functions.
- We developed high standard libraries for Rstudio's Business
 Automation ecosystem for that purpose, specially in order to help us for future developments to improve the entire Sales process.

Skills: RESTful Web Services · Express.js · OAuth · Databases · JavaScript · Node.js · Amazon Web Services (AWS) · AWS Lambda · Salesforce

Full-stack Developer at Amaris, Santiago

April 2019 — June 2021

Consultant role as a Full-stack developer in Angular 8+, Vue.js, Node.js and Typescript for different clients, including Banking and Transport Services (Consorcio Banking and Sodexo).

- Sodexo: We made a complete overhaul of the company's transport service Movilpass (www.movilpass.cl):
 - I helped replace the old frontend with a complete rework of the system made in Angular, improving the overall user experience and ease of use, adding realtime updates and location with Google Maps.
 - I added value by building the frontend with Angular for its scalability and modular design, creating a new development standard in Sodexo, by creating Angular components that can be reused in other Sodexo Angular projects.
- Consorcio: We created a Portability Banking service portal, which helped to get potential new clients to bring their previous banking products from other banks to Consorcio.
 - I helped with the UI and API design work, in Agile MVP deliverables. The first version required to be compliant to Chilean laws in less than weeks from project start, so we helped Consorcio to be out of that hurry and add value to be actually the first bank compliant-ready with Banking Portability. This attracted even more new costumers.
 - I added value to the frontend in Vue.js for their performance and modular design, and easy to embed in the Modyo Platform, which served to host the application.
 - The API made in NestJS had cloud integration with AWS Lambda and API Gateway, so we greatly increased performance and scalability.
 - We used Redis for cache to speed up the endpoints, and CI/CD with Gitlab for automatic deployments.
- Extras: I delivered some training as a coach, with tech talks in front-end technologies (to deliver training courses and workshops) in topics like HTML and Angular.

Skills: Scrum · Kanban · RESTful Web Services · Vue.js · TypeScript · NestJS · Databases · SQL · JavaScript · Angular · Node.js · Salesforce

Java	
JavaScript	
Docker	
TypeScript	
Angular 2+	
NodeJS	
Agile	
Scrum	
Next.js	
Opensearch	
Amazon AWS	
Languages Spanish	
English	

Hobbies

lava

Video Game developer hobbyist in Unreal Engine

Developer at Lagash, Santiago

November 2018 — February 2019

Full-stack developer for a car insurance company called Tanner, using NodeJS and ReactJS.

- We developed a car insurance backoffice web portal fully hosted in Microsoft Azure. I helped bring value with my Javascript knowledge, while at the same time learning Node.js and React/Redux to develop all the features in a big collaborative environment.
- Backend was made in Node with Restify, using Azure's cloud SQL databases for storage. By using Azure and Jenkins for CI/CD, it helped us escalate the microservices easily and deploy the backend and frontend automatically.
- Frontend was made using React + Redux and Material UI for the components, helping us to bring Tanner a lot of value for re-usability of each component for other projects.

Skills: Scrum · Agile · RESTful Web Services · Redux.js · Databases · SQL · JavaScript · Node.js · React.js

Frontend Developer at everis, Santiago

October 2017 — August 2018

Front-end developer in Angular 2+/NodeJS for BCI (Office Banking), as a part of their Migration and Digital Transformation process.

- We worked in a huge Agile project which involved around squads all working on the same product, which was the Office Banking portal.
- I helped bring value to BCI Bank with my JavaScript knowledge, as well as learning Node.js and Angular in order to create new reusable components, based on UX/UI designed elements made by the Bank's Prototype designs, completely aligned with the Bank's corporate image.
- We helped to develop the app's BFF (Backend for Frontend) that was made in Node.js with Express, in order to reuse and chain the distributed microservices made in Java by our Backend team.
- This helped to bring a lot of reusability value and data scrubbing for the Frontend to be as simple and atomic as possible.
- Technologies used: Angular 2+ (native, Material) and NodeJS (with Express).

Skills: Scrum · Kanban · Agile · RESTful Web Services · Angular Material · TypeScript · JavaScript · Angular · Node.js

Developer at Defontana, Santiago

September 2015 — October 2017

.NET and VB Developer in ERP Products, Continuous Integration, and Backend REST solutions for Defontana's Digital Transformation process.

 I helped to bring value to Defontana's main product, their ERP web systems, helping them to migrate their old code into new ASP.NET microservices.

- Technologies used: C#, VB.NET, WCF (microservices), MS Web API, ASP.NET, Razor, SQL Server 2018
- Legacy technologies: VB 6, ASP

 $\begin{tabular}{ll} \textbf{Skills:} & jQuery \cdot .NET \ Framework \cdot ASP.NET \ Web \ API \cdot Visual \ Basic \ .NET \ (NET) \cdot Jenkins \cdot ASP.NET \ Razor \cdot Scrum \cdot Kanban \cdot RESTful \ Web \ Services \ \cdot Databases \cdot Microsoft \ SQL \ Server \cdot SQL \cdot C\# \cdot JavaScript \cdot Visual \ Basic \cdot ASP.NET \cdot .NET \cdot Active \ Server \ Pages \end{tabular}$

Backend Developer at TUTEN, Santiago

April 2015 — August 2015

Backend designer, REST services programmer, Database developer.

- TUTEN is a web/mobile app service that helps people search for professional household services (painting, plumbers, electrical, etc). Works similar to Uber.
- I helped design the database and REST services for TUTEN app's first version, bringing value and their first MVP to life.
- With the team, we travelled to Boston, USA for 3 months to MassChallenge's 2015 startup accelerator conference, to learn how to boost the startup business process and development cycle.
- Technologies used: Java, JAX-RS, Postgres SQL

Skills: PostgreSQL · JAX-WS · Java · Databases · SQL · Java Enterprise Edition

Developer at TAISA Chile, Santiago

January 2011 — March 2015

Software Developer for web and mobile solutions.

- I learned and used .NET (C#, ASP.NET), Java (EE and WebSphere),
 SQL Server, PHP, plus some other legacy software used in Banking like ASP, in order to bring value to TAISA's banking clients.
- It helped me a lot to learn and improve in those languages, as well
 as help bring their clients faster and more responsive experiences
 in their products.
- Clients worked with: Santander, SURA, Corpbanca.
- Technologies used: C#, Java, ASP.NET, ASP, SQL Server.

Skills: jQuery · WebSphere Application Server · .NET Framework · Java · MySQL · Databases · Microsoft SQL Server · SQL · Oracle · C# · PHP · JavaScript · Visual Basic · ASP.NET · .NET · Active Server Pages · Java Enterprise Edition

Education

Computer Sciences, DUOC UC, Santiago

2005 - 2010

Focusing in Microsoft Technologies, and volunteer work in the Microsoft Student Partners program, educational talks in technology to local college.